JAMES WANG

Senior Software Engineer

@ jsoft.star@gmail.com

https://jamestar.netlify.app

Seattle, WA

SUMMARY

A Senior Software Engineer with 10+ years of experience in software development, with a strong command of 5+ programming languages such as HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, TypeScript, and Python, as well as proficiency in designing and implementing efficient algorithms and data structures. Experience spans various domains, including Microsoft and AWS, enabling me to adapt quickly to rapid changes and contribute effectively to diverse projects. Focusing on detail and passion for creating visually appealing and user-friendly experiences. Technically proficient and analytical solver with a calm and focused demeanor. When not working, nice sportsman.

ACHIEVEMENTS



Customized Redux Middleware

Created a customized Redux middleware to display real-time data on the web socket connection.



A New Steganography using Python

Improved steganography using 100% of the new algorithm in the university.

EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Engineer

Toptal

01/2019 - Present

- Built initial structures of 10+ web applications and development environment.
- Systems Architect with a focus on infrastructure, Kubernetes, Terraform, Docker, CICD pipeline, and Linux.
- Developed and maintained 30+ web applications for internal teams built with React, Node.js, and Laravel while providing high test coverage of unit testing, and end-to-end testing.
- High-skilled Senior Front End Developer with expertise in React, TypeScript, and React Hooks, leveraging these technologies to deliver robust and scalable web applications.
- Worked on 10+ serverless web applications with AWS Lambda, AWS DynamoDB, AWS S3, AWS SNS, and so on.
- · Educated on design and frontend development best practices including developing for accessibility.
- · Mentored 20+ new members of the team.

Full Stack Developer

Toptal

= 01/2018 - 12/2018

- · Developed and maintained software applications for various clients, ranging from startups to enterprise-level organizations.
- Completed 5+ web applications, and platforms using MERN, MEAN, and Laravel.
- Extensive experience in cross-platform mobile app development using React Native, delivering seamless user experiences on both iOS and Android platforms.
- Introduced WebRTC to ensure smooth 100% real-time communication, such as video conferencing and real-time data updates.
- Implemented 100% effective and scalable RESTful APIs.
- Contributed to Stripe API with GraphQL, REST and TypeScript, Python.

Software Engineer

Newsela

04/2016 - 12/2017

- Designed and developed 10+ RESTful APIs using Node.JS, Express, Nest, PHP, Laravel, Python, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, MySQL, Redis, Amazon Web Services, Microsoft Azure and Google Cloud Platform.
- Translated 20+ Figma, Adobe XD designs to pixel-perfect and fully responsive design using JavaScript, TypeScript and its libraries, HTML, CSS and SCSS, and LESS CSS preprocessors.
- Developed complicated user interfaces which relied on using web sockets for real-time communication between browser and AWS services.
- Wrote 100% unit test using Jest.

Software Engineer Intern

Google

= 09/2015 - 03/2016

- Collaborated well with a software development team of 10 members.
- Prepared and submitted 50+ reports and other documentation to assist development team members.
- Partnered 50+ team members to learn best practices in software design.

SKILLS

HTML CSS JavaScript PHP Python TypeScript C/C++

SKILLS

React.js	React Native	Next.js A	\ngular \	/ue.js N	ode.js	Nest.js	Laravel	_ V	VordPress	Django	iOS
Socket.IO	Material UI	Tailwind CSS	5 Figma	MySQL	Post	greSQL	MongoDB		Amazon Web S	Services	es
Google Cloud Platform		Microsoft Azur	e RESTfu	ıl API G	raphQL	CI/CD pipeline		Git	Kubernete	Kubernetes Doc	
Jira Jes	st										

EDUCATION

Master's Degree: Computer Science

University of Miami

= 09/2010 - 05/2015

Bachelor's Degree: Computer Science

University of Miami

= 09/2006 - 06/2010

CERTIFICATION

Certified React & Redux Engineer

05/2017 - Issued by Edureka

AWS Certified Developer

04/2022 - Issued by Amazon Web Services (AWS)

Certified Node.js Developer

10/2016 - Issued by OpenJS Foundation

AWARDS



Team Achievement Award

Completed successful Client Relationship Management System in 2022



The Employee of the Toptal

Exceptional performance and contributions in the workplace in 2018